Okay, great. So, I think uh we'll get
started. Okay, thanks. Thanks everyone
for joining us today. It's our great
honor pleasure to have Russ from uh CMU
uh give uh the guest lecture on
multimodel autonomous AI agents. Uh Russ
is a professor at K Melon University and
also VP of research at Meta and
previously he was a director of AI
research at Apple as well. Uh Russ is
someone who doesn't need an
introduction. He has been a longtime uh
well-known uh and also early pioneer uh
in uh deep learning uh AI in general and
has done a lot of really exciting work
uh in the space for a very very long
time. So so I'm personally really
excited uh to have Russ give the guest
lecture uh and uh he's been doing really
exciting work in web agents multi model
autonomous AI agents. So yeah, really
looking forward to it. Thanks, Russ.
Thank you. Thank you, Don. Thanks for
the introductions. Um, so everybody can
hear me. Everything is good, right?
Okay, so today I'm going to talk about
uh multimodel AI agents and sort of give
you a little bit of overview what we've
been doing and some of the work that's
been happening around uh uh that space.
It's a very exciting space. I think that
a lot of people are thinking that the
year 2025 2026 is going to be the year
of agent. So you'll see a lot more work
coming out of out of academia and
industry net space. So um when we think
about large language models right we
think a lot of different sort of you
know innovations that happened in the
last uh in the last few years you know
we see examples of in context learning
zero short learning you have very good
representations of text uh you have uh
general long and coherent text that
these models can generate. sort of world
knowledge uh and so uh amazing things
has been happening in the space of large
language models right but uh what I
would like to talk to you about today is
uh this notion of going beyond just the
language models so you can think of
language models as you know given the
question you know the language model can
generate the answer instead we can try
building systems where that basically
can automate a lot of laborious tasks
right so And a lot of productive tasks
we perform today on the computer
potentially as well as you know many
tasks that we perform on the web could
potentially be automated. Okay. So for
example you know how many of you have
tried setting up AWS instance right uh
on you know my students are basically
saying it's it's a really difficult
process to do. The question is couldn't
you have an agentic model that goes and
sets up AW instance for you right so you
can start running your
experiments or you know wouldn't it be
nice and I think the technology is
getting there a little bit at this point
is you know create a set of PowerPoint
slides to present the content of this
paper right so I give you the paper the
agent reads and sort of goes to the
PowerPoint and organizes slides and
creates and gives you sort of a
presentation of of the paper you know
you know can you automate some of the
tasks that we're doing on Excel going on
the web and uh and so forth, right? You
can imagine a lot of useful uh uh
outcome if you're actually able to
design uh models that can do those
tasks. In this sort of lecture, I'm
going to be focusing primarily on web
agents and sort of give you a little bit
of overview of uh what these models are,
how we evaluate these models. Um and the
idea here is that you know you have a
basic language model, some sort of sort
of foundation model. Obviously you need
some form of text understanding like an
HTML and you also need to have a very
good understanding of uh uh the visual
information like the actual website
itself right so you can think of visual
encoding plus some form of text
understanding that goes into large
language model and that gives you some
form of web grounding right that you can
then use for uh uh performing tasks
tasks on the web and there's been a lot
of work I'm not going to list uh uh
there's been a lot of work in the last
few years where people trying to sort of
understand and trying to build systems
that can they can do these tasks. Let me
show you an example, right? An example
of a system um where I can say suppose I
give the task to my agent. Uh get me to
the page of a good Thai restaurant in
Pittsburgh. It should have at least 200
reviews and 4.3 stars. Pick the one with
the highest rating. Right? And this is
what the system does. Right? So it's
sort of, you know, it goes on Yelp.
It sort of searches for Thai restaurant.
So, it types in autonomously Thai
restaurant, right? It's um it's then
searching through possible restaurant in
Pittsburgh. It sort of finds one of
these restaurants which has 4.5 star
rating. It's a Pussad Garden. It's
actually a pretty good restaurant in
Pittsburgh, right? It's a good Thai
restaurant. Now, it's complete. Now
imagine I'm asking it to say well get me
a reservation at this uh for two people
at the earliest date and use my name JY
co who is the student who built this uh
and the phone number right and so the
agent goes on Google finds this
particular restaurant looks at the dates
looks at the next available date and
actually uh successfully making a
reservation right um and putting the
phone number and then basically stops
because you need to get a confirmation
to actually book something right uh So
it basically says you know in summary in
the next action I'll perform is stop
unable to proceed without confirmation
code for 30 f instructions to complete
the reservation right. So you sort of
have this notion of the agent that takes
tasks. It generates chain of thoughts
within thinking and then uh takes takes
the action. Or I can give the example of
help me navigate to the shirt that has
on it. Right? So it goes on Amazon um
it's trying to basically look for
something similar and uh you know finds
a shirt that has something similar,
right?
um these are the examples that are
heavily cherrypicked uh out of I think
that we've tried maybe like you know 30
times and out of 30 times one of them
succeeded right so that basically means
that these systems do not are not really
uh working very well at this point but
uh it has the potential of you know give
you a flavor of what these systems can
do I think in today's world like open
eyes operator kind of like sort of you
know uh moving in that direction is one
of one of the uh very strong models
that's that's out there. So today I'm
going to talk about three different
things, right? I'm going to talk about
visual web arena which is a way of
evaluating uh multimodal agents on uh
some of the realistic visual tasks. I'll
talk about some of the inference time
algorithm what we call a three search
algorithm for large language model
agents um which sort of allows you to uh
uh potentially uh do interesting search
apply interesting search techniques to
find uh necessary information on the web
and then the last part I'll talk a
little bit about uh some of the way of
scaling up data for training these
agents because one of the aspects of of
of of uh of these agents in general is
the availability of data what can you do
online and how can you get the data
online? Right? So, let's look at the uh
visual web arena. Um, one of the earlier
versions uh was uh uh was developed by
folks at CMU. Uh right, it was done by
um Shyen Shuan Zu and Frank Zu. Um
they've introduced the notion of webin
which is a fairly realistic environment
at the moment. It has popular categories
like shopping, Reddit and GitLab which
is equivalent to Amazon and Reddit and
GitHub. It's a self-hosted open-source
essentially environment which is re
reimple reimp implementation of the
environment and the data comes from real
websites from Amazon wrote uh Reddit and
GitHub and what's interesting about this
environment and I'll talk about this the
tasks are fairly easy for humans about
78 success rate but very difficult for
language models at a time they've
reported numbers like 40%. The only
problem with this particular task is
that task are designed to use just HTML
source code, right? And we found that a
lot of times when whenever you're
dealing with HTML and JavaScript, it's
it's it's a very messy type of
representation interactive elements that
when you're interacting with the
environments, they don't get displayed
correctly HTML. There is like Java CSS
code and it's it's very hard to kind of
like process them in context length.
HTML pages can be fairly complex like
they can easily feel feel up to 100,000
tokens right if you kind of like trying
to uh uh look at that. So um and this is
how it sort of looks like you know you
have this uh you know kind of like HTML
based representation spatial layout is
also not conveyed very well in in HTML
so it looks like just a texton
representation
um it's very difficult to deal with
right um just because HTML is messy so
we've tried building what we call visual
web arena uh which is we try to build
and track the process of multimodel
agents agent that actually have visual
grounding. Um, so we've designed these
visually grounded tasks to test the
abilities of these models and it's sort
of inspired by web arena. So we call it
visual web arena. Um and you have visual
inputs and outputs um that allows you to
work with unique and interesting sort of
and something that's uh real world and
again we sort of uh have the
environments of what we call one-stop
shop which is uh essentially Amazon like
environment Reddit and OS class which is
more like a craggly stack of environment
the class type of environment right so
let me show you um and then you can
think about that you know you have some
representation I have some visual input
and I ask you to um uh to solve
something that actually requires visual
grounding and visual understanding. So,
let me show you some examples of of
this. Let's say um I ask I give you the
task. I ask you to find this exact bike.
So, I'm looking for this bike that's
listed for 35500 and post the comment
offering $10 less than the asking price.
Okay? And this is what the agent has to
do. Again, it's a simulator. It's a
fully self-hosted environment, right?
You sort of go, you navigate, you find
this bike, and then you basically make
uh a posting by offering, you know, $10
less than what the asking price is,
right? That's just one one example,
right? And that basically you you've
completed uh successfully completed that
task. And I can imagine in the future
there's going to be agents that's going
to be bargaining on your behalf and
there's going to be agents on the other
side that's going to be, you know,
making you counter offers. Here's
another example. Let's say I ask you buy
the cheapest color photo printer and
send it to Emily's place as shown in the
image. And what you can see this image
is upside down. Um, which makes it
fairly difficult for existing models to
sort of look at this and actually figure
out what the address should be, right?
So some of these kind of like tasks we
designed so that it wouldn't be that
easy for the models to to solve. Um, and
so what the agent needs to do, it sort
of needs to go, it needs to find, it
needs to sort by price, it gets the
printer, it adds to the cart, then it
goes and it starts completing, you know,
the address. So, you know, it has pull
down menu. So, it sort of, you know,
looks fairly realistic, right? And then
you go and then you place the order. And
when you end up in this state, that
particular state, that basically means
that you've successfully accomplished
the task. Right? Um, again, just to
reemphasize, it's a simulation. Uh, it's
not actually doing it on the real web.
It's a self-hosted, uh, uh, environment.
Here's another one where requires you to
sort of jump between two different uh,
websites. You can ask, what's the 2022
total nominal GDP of the area that
produce most sugar cane in the year of
2021 and billion, right? And that's your
landing page. What's interesting here is
that you're essentially asking the model
to understand the images because if you
look at the year 2021 that's over here
and you look um I think in this case
Asia produced more sugar cane than than
Brazil or the other way around Brazil
produced more sugarcane than Asia. So
you kind of like have to look at these
graphs and understand um what's uh which
country you should be looking at. Right?
So if you kind of zoom in, you can sort
of say, okay, uh that was I think that
was Asia that produced more sugarcane.
So you have to go on Wikipedia and then
find find the answer, right? And the
answer is
339 trillion
um GDP. So you can kind of see that you
have to sort of have this visual
grounding. You have to understand
images. You have to understand graphs um
to to solve some of these tasks. All
right. So the way that the environment
is represented, we can think of this
environment as a pom dp environment. So
this partial observable mark of decision
process. So you have states, you have
actions, observations and transition
function, right? And so for those of you
who've worked in reinforcement learning
or who've been sort of dealing with mark
of decision MTPs, that should be
familiar. And that was the goal to
design the environment in such a way
that it becomes an MDP so that you can
potentially you know train your favorite
uh reinforcement learning algorithms on
this. So the environment itself have
observations whether it's an HTML
whether it's the visual representation
like the actual website itself uh and
something that we call accessibility
tree which is a cleaned up
representation of HTML.
You have a set of actions and the set of
actions is actually fairly diverse set
of actions, right? You can clear click
on particular element. You can hover
over particular element. This is an
interesting one. You can type in a
particular element and text, right? So
you can think it's not just a set of
discrete actions, you know, basically
you can type in whatever, right? If
you're searching for something or you're
filling um uh certain
boxes, you can have a new tab. So you
can jump to uh a new website, you can
focus on a particular top, you can close
the top, you can go particular URL, you
can go forward, go backwards, scroll up,
scroll down and then you have an action
called stop and then answer. Stop is the
action where the model basically says
okay I've solved the task stop and then
I give you the final the final answer.
Um in this particular environment you
have deterministic transition function.
You have the state that generates the
HTML page and given the state and an
action you generate the next state and
that the next state generation is
actually deterministic basically meaning
that if you're on a particular website
and you click on a particular element or
you type something there is only one uh
there's no stoasticity so you know gets
you to the next state and we also define
reward functions and reward function is
primarily to to evaluate when you've
successfully solved u a task. So it's a
fairly sparse reward signal that we get
in this environment. Okay. But let me
show you just walk you through what the
model actually needs to do here. Right.
So what the model needs to do is it you
know has to start on the on the
homepage. So here you're trying to find
the cheapest uh printer and you have to
navigate to the printer category right
in terms of the actions that you need to
take. Then you have to sort by
descending order. So if you click sort
by price right then you click on the
cheapest color printer. You have to
choose what's the cheapest one. So you
kind of like have to understand how much
each printer cost and you have to choose
the cheapest one. Then you have to add
it to the shopping cart. That's another
step. You have to proceed to checkout.
That's another step. Then you have to
fill in the form correctly, right? With
with the information given to you in
this image. Um and then you have to
place the order. So if you look at the
entire trajectory here, it's fairly
complex trajectory, right? The model has
to sort of reason about what it's seeing
on the web. It has to understand what I
mean by the cheapest. Um, so it has to
have a notion of sorting. Um, then it
has to really understand good multimodel
abilities to understand what what I'm
seeing in the images. Uh, what's the
address and I have to go in and fill in
the address, right, with the right
information. So if you look at it, it's
it's not a very trivial task uh, uh, to
accomplish, right? And that's just one
of uh, a thousand tasks that we've
designed.
So in terms of the distribution of tasks
across the websites um uh you know we've
looked at how difficult those tasks are.
We have I think we have 950 tasks in
total close to thousand tasks and you
can see about 15% are easy. Basically
what that means is that it's easy in
terms of reasoning difficulty and easy
in terms of visually understanding what
I'm asking you. Basically means you have
to do only a few clicks to actually
solve the task. And then you sort of
have this corner here which is fairly
difficult uh reasoning difficulty. So I
really have to understand what I'm
seeing in the image. And visual
difficulty uh and reasoning difficult
basically means that I have to click on
a lot of things and kind of explore to
to successfully uh uh accomplish uh this
particular task. Right? So in this
particular environment you can actually
split and try to understand is it my
visual models I'm missing or is it my
reasoning uh is is is missing.
uh here's how we evaluating uh these in
this environment. So we have execution
based evaluation. So for example a lot
of times we want to find the exact
match. So if I'm ask you the question
what's the ising number of the company
that occupies the largest portion of
Warren Buffett portfolio then I kind of
like go to Wikipedia I find Warren's
Buffford portfolio and then I sort of
get the information and I need to get
this exact number. Sometimes if I said
add something like that to the man's
wear who whatever this man is wearing to
my wish list then I kind of like you
know find something and I basically have
visual QA like is this a polo shirt yes
or no is this a green shirt and so forth
right um and then you have you know
sometimes when you're looking for
something you say it has to include you
know above 200 or below 30 above 20,000
below 30,000 and so forth right so you
can kind of like have these verifiers
that once you once I give you the final
state. I can actually run these
verifiers and sort of tell you have you
solved the task or not. And for a lot of
these prompts, there's only one
solution, right? Because the environment
is not, you know, the full internet.
It's fairly constrained, but at least
you can verify whether your model
actually successfully solved the task or
not. Now, when we think about LLM's uh
or visual language VLMs agents, visual
language models, um the way to think
about this is is the following, right?
Um, one thing I can do is I can look at
the HTML and try to, you know, use that
as a representation into my uh into my
LLM. It's also cluttered with a lot of
unnecessary information. You know, it
has a long and confusing context.
There's been a lot of work where people
sort of doing markups where they're
trying to identify the relevant parts of
the HTML and trying to use that. There's
another representation is to use
something that's called set of marks
which is a simplified representations.
uh so what it does is it basically puts
bounding boxes around elements around
clickable elements right so whether I
can click on certain elements or not and
that's something that you can get from
uh from any HTML right so that's set of
marks representation something that you
can do both of these representation have
advantages and disadvantages set of
marks is useful because actually
visually I understand what I'm seeing in
the image and what I can click on um but
it's also very cluttered type of
representation and there is a third type
of representation that people are now
beginning to use which is coordinate
based representation where I'm just
trying to predict the coordinate of
where I need to click. So ultimately
it's probably going to be combination of
both HTML set of marks some kind of
coordinate based
representation and the way you can think
about these sort of representation is
that if let's say I have a original web
page I can use the set of marks
representation right so I can put the
bounding boxes and have ids for each box
and sort of have some representation
what each box is actually doing and
perhaps have some form of captioning of
each image. So I have this sort of set
of set of marks elements in the text as
well as the actual visual
representation, right? And if I say if
I'm trying to find this post, navigate
to the comment section of it, then you
pass it to the LLM or VLM agent and then
the agent actually executes a precise
action to to do next. For example, I
want to click on element ID 31 and
element ID 31 is one of the elements
here, right? And so again the way that
we typically have a representation I
have a goal I get an observation I
represent it using set of marks that
goes to the multimodel large language
models both the text and the image as
well as the goal and the model generates
chain of thoughts. So in this case it
would generate listing step by step. The
objective is to navigate to the food the
post and and so forth. Um to navigate to
this listing I need to click on the
comment linked associated with the
sushi. In summary, my next action will
be, you know, I'll perform action click
34. And again, that's the action that
you're clicking. Right? So that's one
particular action that the model is um
uh is taking uh and then it goes once
you click on that particular element,
the the simulator will go to the next
web page, the next the next state. And
then you repeat this uh you repeat this
process, right? And here again the
action is you take a particular action
uh from the list of actions that that
I've mentioned
before. Now if I look at um sort of
baseline models and kind of try to
understand which models are working well
and which models are not. Uh what's
interesting is that if I only use text
only based representation
um then I hit something like 9%
accuracy. If I use text plus caption, so
if I caption any any visual information,
any images that I have on the web pages,
you know, you have improvement. If I
actually try to use multimodal model,
you get further improvement. If I use
set of marks representation, sort of
like I understand clickable elements and
what I can do, you get a little bit of
improvement as well. So you kind of go
from 9% to something like 18%. And then
you get human level performance. And the
human level performance hits close to
you know in this case for visual web it
was hitting something like 85 86 uh uh
accuracy right so there's a big gap
between what people are capable of doing
it and what existing models are capable
of doing um this was interesting the way
that we've collected the data is we
actually asked students at
CMU to solve these tasks we give them
the prompts we give them the tasks we
give them the environment and they just
interact with the environment and then
they end in a state and then to evaluate
using our execution based evaluation
whether they success successfully solved
the task. What's interesting is that we
found that you know humans were not at
100%. Uh right and what's interesting a
lot of mistakes that people make are
kind of silly mistakes. Uh so for
example if I ask you to find uh you know
if I ask you to say well find me the
cheapest bicycle right uh that has these
specific constraints or these
conditions. I want it to be black. I
want it to be of this color. I want it
to be less than $2,000. Go find me the
cheapest bike. Uh what people tend to
do, people tend to kind of like go
through the go through the simulator.
They look at they find one bike, they
find the second bike, and then they
basically say, "Okay, I'm tired of
looking for anything else." Right? So I
have two bicycles, I take the cheapest
one and say, "I'm done." H whereas
actually there are 10 bicycles, right?
That satisfy the constraint. So people
are just not very good at information
seeking tasks or at least we didn't pay
uh students enough. We gave them pizza
uh to to kind of like go and you know
spend more than a few minutes to solve
these tasks. So majority of the kind of
information seeking task is where people
were not really good at and sometimes
people were kind of like a little bit uh
you know they would solve the task but
they would forget to click on you know
you know place the order. So they would
solve the task, they would add to the
cart, they find the right thing, but
they forget to click on, you know, place
the order and they forgot to and if if
they forget to, you know, uh, place the
order, then our system basically says
that, well, you haven't solved it,
right? Because they actually haven't
haven't bought the item. Um, and so, you
know, this is an interesting uh part
because I think that agentic systems
should be able to solve these tasks.
system should be much better at
information seeking and finding sort of
uh uh the information just because it
requires less uh cognitive load whereas
people are not very good at doing
that. If I look at sort of you know
trying to understand you know where we
are uh with these models you can kind of
like see that llama you know the the
older versions of llama they all were
kind of like really bad. If I have
accessibility tree plus captions, a lot
of these models would kind of, you know,
go higher. And then once I have
multimodels, you have much better
representation. And then once I have,
you know, the multimodel models at that
time looking Gemini Pro and GPT4, I
think GPT40 now hit something like 90%.
So like these models do do climb, they
do better, uh, but they still far below
what people can do. Uh, right. Even the
best models today are sitting around
20% accuracy right in terms of solving
these
tasks. And here's one example I wanted
to show is it's an interesting example
where uh the GPT model was able to
successfully solve it. I ask you I don't
like the author of this image from the
posts, one of the posts. Can you help me
uh block them? And the engine would
actually go it would sort of click on
the right things. It would find the
post. it would go to the settings and
through sort of executing multiple
clicks it would actually block a
specific user right just as an example
like you give it this instruction and
the model would actually go um and and
do that and this sort of has this notion
of that I'd like to think about web
agent architectures and I'll I'll make
that reference later on for physical
agents uh but you can think about these
sort of architectures where you know you
observe some input say a web page um you
do some form of parsing right of the web
page whether it's visual and HTML or
some kind of compressed representation
of HTML plus visual understanding you
have an objective right and the
objective is what I need to do and a lot
of times what uh what a lot of these
models would do is they would generate
high level plan right they would
generate a plan of how to execute how
you should proceed to solve the task and
then you kind of you know uh execute the
low-level actions which is clicking on
the specific element right and that sort
of goes in loop
you know, you can refine the highle
plan, you can execute a low-level action
up until you hit a stop action, which
basically means that the agent is done.
Uh, I think I've solved the task. Okay?
And, you know, you can think of planning
as, you know, uh, as a system. There's
been some work on building these
hierarchical systems where, you know,
for example, step one, I can say,
navigate me to a particular category,
right? Step two, um, you know, I I want
to sort based on the rating of that
category, and that would be two level
actions. You're selecting and then
you're sorting, right? And then maybe,
you know, you select an item under $20.
And then maybe you're buying a selected
item, right? You need to buy it, and
that's three lowlevel actions. You add
to the cart, you proceed to the
checkout, and you do shipping. Um, so
there is some sort of work right now
that's trying to have the planning model
that actually, you know, plans what you
need to do, and then and then you
execute those. So visual web arena we
think of it as a step towards building
general purpose agents all right it's
it's a simulator so you can evaluate
those models um tasks that we design are
not very consequential at this point you
know they don't really represent
significant economic value at this point
and and we've designed these tasks to be
simpler because the current large
language model agents or AI agents do
not even do well on these tasks the gap
is still fairly significant
um and the longerterm question is can we
automate productive
economically uh valuable tasks, right?
Um, one of the interesting failure modes
that we see this these models and and
again we're fixing those a lot of that
is sort of progresses as the models
become uh better and better. But one of
the things that we're seeing is is this
notion of long horizon uh reasoning and
planning right so models sometimes
oscillate between two web pages or
sometimes they get stuck in the loop. So
it's you know I'm trying to do something
I go to this web page and then I go back
and then I go forward and I go back. So
this is the notion of persistent memory.
A lot of times sort of you know memory
is missing. So good representation of
what I've done so far um is missing. Of
course I can concatenate every single
web page I visited with every single
HTML but that becomes fairly cumbersome,
right? You need to have a good
persistent representation of the memory.
A lot of times you know models would
correctly start on performing task and
then undoing them. I don't know why.
It's just basically means they don't
don't have very good reasoning
abilities. And a lot of times agents
tend to stop uh exploration execution
too early. So instead of exploring what
are the possibilities there, they
actually try to do something and then
you stop and you basically execute the
stop action and says like I I you know I
can't solve the task. I'm not seeing how
I can solve the
task. Um and there's also some failures
in visual processing. So sometimes you
can click on the wrong items identifying
specific items in complex web pages.
There is also you know they lack a
little bit of spatial reasoning like if
you're asking the question what are the
prices of products in the first row you
kind of like have to understand what the
first row is but the second row and like
what's the middle row right so certain
spatial you know understanding is
missing but I think those things will
potentially get better as we sort of uh
um can get the data for training these
models right so what we need to do we
need to do a lot more to close the gap u
definitely reasoning and planning over
long horizon And that's I'll talk a
little bit about this, but that's one of
the key failure modes. Uh we also need
to allow agents to search. You can think
of it as executing and coordinating
multiple instances in parallel and
asking for clarifications and
confirmations, right? So a lot of times
search is actually, you know, you can
think of it as test time inference
technique. Basically tries to explore
possibilities to figure out what's the
right way to solve the task and asking
for clarification. And this is where
uncertainty estimation comes in. It's
also fairly challenging where you
basically the model has to understand
it. is confused and then he has to go
and ask humans for for clarifications or
guidance and obviously you need strong
you know visual language code models and
also identifying appropriate levels of
abstractions for agents like you know do
you rely on screenshots what you're
seeing visually do you rely on HTML or
maybe you rely on APIs a lot of you know
there's a lot of websites that would
have API so maybe instead of actually
going through the web you actually go
through API calls right and again I
think that multimodel models here be
becomes very important because a lot of
real world task will require some form
of visual grounding right so for example
if you you know if you're interacting
with powerpoint if you're interacting
with Photoshop right a lot of it yes you
can do it through API but a lot of
things are also done through visual
grounding and visual understanding
um so we definitely need to train and
build stronger visual language
models so that kind of like gives me
this notion of of visual visual web
arena which is the environment that we
use for doing evaluation Now let's talk
uh about um uh the research uh or we can
think of it as again test time
inference. One interesting thing about
uh agentic um agents in general is that
you have this notion of exponential uh
error compounding right. So for example
you know uh if your model is accurately
can can be accurate at onestep
prediction at 90%. Then if you're
executing you know 30 actions then your
accuracy goes down to 4%. Right? Um so
you basically need to be very very
accurate. So you need to be very precise
in terms of like executing each step in
order to be able successfully you know
solving long horizon tasks and that's
pretty well known in anytime you have
sequential decision-m process uh you
have this issue right uh the errors do
compound over time uh which makes it uh
which makes it uh a very very difficult
uh difficult task. Uh so what happens
here? Well, local decisions have global
consequences, right? So, for example,
let's say I ask you the question, add
coconut milk to my cart. Well, I can
click on element ID 31 or maybe and that
gives me to the next state or maybe I
can click element ID 24 that gets me to
the next state, right? And then so
forth. There's sort of different
choices. There's a lot of actions. The
action space could be exponential,
especially if I'm doing searching as
well, right? So I can type text. Um and
so you can imagine that each one of
these sort of leads to a trajectory
right once I execute the trajectory um
then potentially I can evaluate you know
which one is right which one is wrong
and let's say you know basically this
state gives me the right outcome and all
the other states don't and especially
you know if you're executing actions you
know 30 40 50 actions um that becomes uh
very challenging and if you have a
policy right now that you know you can
think of uh uh VLM as your policy that
basically predicts the probability 0.5
you should click on this section and
probability 0.1 you should click on this
section then obviously you know finding
the correct path is going to be very
difficult right so you know you
basically have to you have to be able to
explore the environment very efficiently
right in this sort of exponential uh in
this exponential uh
space now one of the things that turns
out to work Okayish uh or at least as a
first step is doing search by repeated
sampling. All right, it's a very simple
idea, very easy idea. You sample action
from your model until you hit the stop
action. Okay, so let's say you sample
this path. Um and then you evaluate the
resulting trajectory. So you look at the
trajectory and you can say have you
solved the task or did you not solve the
task? Right? If you have a verifiers
that can tell you that you solve the
task, then you know whether it's success
or not success, right? And if it's a not
success, then you repeat, right? This
would be an instance of what's called
rejection sampling, right? You generate
the trajectory, you look at the outcome,
and if you didn't solve it, you generate
another trajectory, right? Um this is a
very simplistic you know way uh
rejection uh called rejection sampling.
You basically sample until you hit the
right answer. Uh it's fairly inefficient
but it's surprising that a lot of work
uh that's happening right now for
example in space of reasoning like
models like 01 03 or deepseek they're
essentially doing exactly this. They're
essentially doing rejection sampling. I
give you the math problem. I start
generating thinking tokens up until I
get the right answer. Right? And so I
start with simpler prompts. I I
generate, you know, sometimes right
answers, sometimes wrong answers. I use,
you know, reinforcement learning to
reinforce positive and then de reinforce
negative and sort of start scaling it
up. So the simple idea of rejection
sampling is essentially what's driving
uh a lot of innovation right now in in
reasoning capabilities, right? which is
amazing and and very was very surprising
to me that it actually works. Um so
we've sort of started looking at exactly
the same problem but for us uh in this
particular domain it's not that you can
generate you know thinking tokens and
then you basically get the answer here
you actually have to execute actions in
the environment and you change the state
of the environment right which makes it
uh much more uh much more difficult. So
here you do rejection sampling and
hopefully at some point you'll hit the
right uh the right answer. What happens
is that you know repeated sampling tends
to help right so here's the number of 10
runs and this is what we call passet uh
pass at 10 which basically means that
you know if you're running uh your model
10 times uh one of you know like in
terms of like you know you you hit like
15% probability of of getting the right
answer right so the more you sample the
probability that you'll hit the right
answer among these samples is kind kind
of you know is increasing and that's
what this graph is showing. All right.
And however you know the space is
exponentially large, right? So can we
guide this exploration? And the key idea
here is to apply the value function to
intermediate nodes. Um it's a very old
idea. Um but you know you can apply it
actually in this in this space as well.
So how does this work? Um so the idea is
to basically do a form of a best first
search algorithm with a few tweaks. So
what are the ingredients of the
algorithm? So the baseline agent
proposes actions. The baseline agent
actually says okay here's two actions
that I can take right these are the most
probable action according to uh the base
model according to your original policy.
uh you have to have a uh have a way to
backtrack in the environment, right? So
that basically means you're in this
state, you want to be able to backtrack
to the original state. Um this is
sometimes difficult to do especially in
uh web environments because some actions
you can't backtrack from and these
actions that we call destructive actions
like um you know if I place the order I
can't just go back and unplace it. Uh
right that's just one example. So we'll
talk a little bit about this. And then
you also have to have a value function.
You can think of a value function that
takes the input whatever your
representation is. Plus it takes a
sequence of previous observations or
previous steps and outputs a score. Uh
and you can think a value function uh
essentially uh looking at the expected
value uh expected reward. um think of it
as you know in our settings think of it
as uh the probability of successfully
solving the task right so it's a number
between zero and one that basically says
if I'm in this state and my value
function is you know 0.5 then the
probability of me
succeeding is you know 50%. And if the
value function of in this state is 3
then the probability of me succeeding is
30%. Right? So maybe this state is
better than this state. So you have to
have a good value function right and
these are kind of values that you can
associate uh and what we've done in this
work is we basically using LLM as a
judge so we uh in this case you know you
take a GPT4 you take the full trace the
full trajectory and you're asking the
model to say you know uh is uh you know
how good the state is in terms of
solving a particular task. So there's a
way to sort of you know uh use use this
LLM as a judge. Um there's a few tricks
of self-consistency that you can use but
essentially you can just use um a large
language model as a judge to judge each
state. Ultimately I do believe that the
next generation models will create their
own value functions. You'll train your
own value function that basically will
guide this exploration. Okay. So how
does this work? Let's say that I give
you a task, right? The task instruction
is can you add this and the other canned
fruit of the same brand that looks like
this but red instead of brown to the
comparison page. Okay, so how does this
work? Well, you take the action, right?
And then at this point you have three
possible actions to take, right? They
all have a probability. They all have a
value function of 045, right? So you
pick one of them, you proceed and then
you go to the next kind of state and
your value function decreases. So you
basically say okay I'm actually maybe
I'm on the wrong path to solving this
task and then I backtrack and I take
another action right so I backtrack to
the previous state and I take uh the
other action and let's say here I go in
my probability increases I go in my
probability increases and then I hit a
particular state where you know I'm not
actually going to solve this task right
because you know my value of the state
is actually pretty small because I ended
up in a very long in a very wrong state
So then I have to be able to backtrack
again from this state. I have to be able
to backtrack back to the original state,
right? And then go and and sort of you
know again take the next states you know
and then if it's if it's bad backtrack
and eventually solve the task right so
you can sort of see that it's more uh
expensive. Um there are different ways
of exploring but the key here that
drives a lot of this exploration is the
value of of the state right which
basically is telling you how good the
particular state is in terms of solving
the task and you can kind of like you
know spot the errors early on and say no
no no backtrack and and restart uh
again. Um so it's a little bit better
than just doing random rejection
sampling because here you're doing
guided uh guided uh um
exploration. Um it's very similar to you
know some of you familiar with alpho uh
setting right where you basically have
um an environment where you have a value
of the state and then you know you try
to explore which actions to take and you
sort of evaluate those states given the
value function that that you
have. And so if we look at the results,
what we found is that you know uh for
web arena you know there is pretty
decent improvement in terms of the
ability to solve these tasks. For the
visual web arena we also see you know
quite reasonable improvements by using
this exploration. It's more expensive
but u uh and so so we can we we do see
that uh these sort of search at test
time actually improves uh models ability
to to solve the task. uh or at least to
solve some of the tasks. You can still
see that we're still very far away from
hitting like 90% accuracy, right? Uh but
nonetheless, it's actually a progress
where we're progressively uh uh
improving and we do sort of see that if
you look at the sub uh if you look at
the success rate, right? C0 indicates no
search and then you know the more node
expansions you have, the better your
performance is. And then you can also
sort of look at the success rate
relative to um you know how you want to
expand you know do you control the depth
uh versus the breadth and sort of again
how much you want to explore versus
what's the branching factor. Um and then
if we kind of you know keep exploring
and doing the branching then the
accuracy tends to go up just because the
model is able to explore possible
different uh uh different uh
possibilities like or different
environments. A lot of times what we see
in in sort of in these settings is that
you know if I ask it to buy a blue polar
shirt you know if if you don't do this
search the model let's say goes and
let's say it clicks on the wrong thing
and it ends up on a web page that only
has blue polo shirts right so you're
asking black polar shirt and gives you
blue polar shirts and then the model
says well there are no black polo shirts
because I'm only seeing blue polar
shirts I can't solve the task done right
and obviously this is the case that if
you can backtrack can sort of explore,
you will find the right answer, right?
So this notion of of search is actually
becomes fairly important, right? And and
and and such. And so and we also found
that having a good value function is
essential, right? Uh there is still a
lot of headroom for improving the base
policy. Obviously, your base policy has
to be good. It can't just take random
actions. If your base policy is if your
base model is actually pretty weak, then
you know you'll just be taking random
actions and there's only that much you
can do with with exploration. Um uh but
you sort of need to improve both right
uh and you can kind of like see if you
use different value functions you know
then the performance is actually
improved like with no search if you sort
of like say lava which is a weaker
version you get the improvement. If you
use something you know for all type of
models then you know you have uh so if
you have a better value function kind of
like looks at the full trajectory then
it's uh it's you you have improvements
in performance and the interesting thing
is that using uh LLM as a judge judging
whether the trajectory is good or bad is
much easier than predicting what the
next action you should take right um or
what what the next sort of element you
should click on what you should be
searching on and so uh That's why sort
of you know starting using value
function as an LLM initially I think
it's it's a reasonable thing to do but
obviously you want to be able to to
improve this. Here's just some examples,
right? You can basically say, I recall
seeing this exact item on the site. Help
me find the most recent post of it. I
recall seeing it in either collectibles
or antique section, right? So the models
would kind of like go in the starting
state. It would sort of explore and
eventually find that particular uh
posting. Right? Or this one where I can
say, hey, I like this. I need something
like this in my apartment. Can you add
one uh can you add one to my wish list?
So the model kind of like have to go. it
has to sort of like search through
different environments, find this
specific item and add it to your wish
list, right? Uh it would be great if you
have something like like like that,
right? You take a picture of something
and and you basically tell your agent,
hey, go and find it on Amazon, Best Buy,
wherever. Uh get me the best price for
this, right? And and you know, see where
I can buy
it. Just just as an example. Now in
terms of limitations of of this, well
search is pretty slow, right? Um so you
obviously need uh a fast way of doing
backtracking. We sort of did the
backtracking in a relatively naive way.
You store all actions in a queue and
then take them again to get to the
original state, right? So if you're
taking 20 kind of like actions, you
store what you've done so far and then
to go back, you re rerun uh that again.
So it's not very efficient uh what we've
done. I think it just requires sort of
like infrastructure uh uh work. And the
other interesting piece is dealing with
destructive actions, right? Certain
things on the web are very difficult to
undo. Um especially if you're operating
on the real web for testing these
models. Uh you can't order the item and
then unorder it, right? It's not like
you can order the item and then your
model says, you know what, that was
actually the wrong order. Let's try
ordering something else. You can't do
that, right? Um and so the other thing
that you can't unfortunately do in the
real web is it's it's very hard to um uh
do some form of learning in the real web
uh because anything that changes the
state of the environment is actually
fairly difficult, right? I can't go on
on United and start booking flights from
Pittsburgh to San Francisco to learn how
to book the flights, right? Because if
I'm sort of like exploring and I'm kind
of like saying, why don't I click here?
Well, maybe I should click here and then
and then maybe I should kind of like try
to book this flight and then maybe it's
wrong and try to book this other flight.
And so, um, it becomes a little bit
tricky to do because essentially United
will block you or or United will
basically say, "Oh, so many people are
trying to book flights from Pittsburgh
to San Francisco. Maybe we should like
increase the prices, right?" Um, so you
have to be careful how you actually
operating in in in the real world. So,
what's the current work? Obviously
search as a policy improvement function.
You can use search as a way of finding
the correct trace or the correct
trajectory and you can use this
potentially in either in reinforcement
type of learning algorithm or actually
in SFT to try to you know um um
fine-tune on this improving value
function by fine-tuning instead of
prompting. So if you you know if you can
improve the value function by using
Monte Carlo rollouts um you can do that.
um obviously exploring trade-off between
improving baseline agent how much your
base model has to be versus how much
more search you do you have to do at
inference time right and today we sort
of see this notion of test time
inference you know scaling loss where
well if I if I do search for more I can
probably get a better answer and I think
that it's true but it's sort of both
models need to improve right your base
model needs to be better and also search
needs to be more efficient
um and obviously
you know, one of the biggest questions
if we don't have a simulator of the web
environment, right? How can we collect
data at scale? And that's one of um uh
one of the interesting problems that we
also started looking at uh what can we
do and how we can collect uh the data at
scale because the interesting thing
about agentic uh models in general is
that it's the kind of data that's very
difficult to find on the web, right?
Like so what what we see with existing
LLMs is that you know I can crawl the
web I can scrape images and HTML and
then I can pre-train these model just
doing the next talk and prediction right
for Gentic work it's very difficult
right it's very difficult for me to say
hey give me a whole bunch of examples
and show me how am I should be booking
my flight from Pittsburgh to to San
Francisco all right or show me in this
setting you know I like like you know
hey I like something like this add me to
my wish list right It's not like you can
find a lot of these examples on the web
and you know uh of uh of uh examples of
people showing you how to solve these
tasks right so this notion of giving the
task and the full trajectory of how you
should take actions and solve the task
is actually very limited data that we
have today. Uh right in fact we don't
have any of that data. uh a lot of
companies they essentially collecting
this data in-house by asking people to
you know solve these tasks and do like
massive massive annotations. So the
question for us was how can we collect
the data at scale and that gives me to
the third point which is how can we at
least try thinking about um what we can
do
here. So, um, as I've mentioned before,
agents suffer from a data problem,
right? And you can see the gap is still
pretty big.
Um, and when we think about LLMs, the
way that we're training them today, a
lot of times they often trained online,
I just collect bunch of data. Um, and
then I deploy them as zero shots as
agents, right? And then, you know, I
collect a lot of data, I do some form of
supervised fine-tuning. Um, at least
that's what's happening in academia. And
then you know I try to deploy them and
see how they work. Uh right the question
is can we somehow go on the real web and
generate synthetic tasks to unlock this
largecale training of agents. Okay. And
uh uh you know the the question is you
know how can we again uh get these
models to generate something synthetic
and actually you know build something
that we can train on and improve our
improve our edges without human uh
intervention or without actually you
know task generated by humans because uh
it's fairly expensive to ask humans to
to generate or or you know create those
tasks. Um so one of the things that
we've been trying to build is we've been
trying to build this internet scale
training for agents that we call insta
uh which is um you know the idea here is
we using llama models to generate and
verify syn synthetic agentic tasks. So
we're thinking about three stages right
there is a data a task generation stage
right for example I can ask the model to
say find me a codebase for generating
images with flex one point with flex.1
right um that's the first task I'll show
you examples of how we can do that the
second task is
evaluation actually executing this task
and then trying to see whether you know
the model solved the task um and then
the third step is actually collection
big uh uh
basically collecting it at scale. But
you can think of this environment is
that the model proposes tasks. The model
executes those tasks. The model then
evaluates those tasks and then you know
if it successfully says yeah I proposed
the task I executed this task on the
real web. I evaluated I think I've
solved the task then that becomes a very
useful data for uh for training our
agents. Okay. So let's see how how we
can do
uh so for example given the web domain
uh for example you know there's a domain
just random domain
mercifaries it's a it's a website in the
UK and we can ask the system to propose
realistic task that an average user
could complete in one session so there's
a certain system prompt that we're
asking the model to uh to generate the
task and what's interesting that if you
look at llama 70B 3.1 I think we also
training on llama 3.3 which is actually
better has better results so these
models you know continue improving so if
I ask the model to describe what is this
website about it's actually pretty good
you know it sort of says well this
particular website is official website
for famous mercifi service in Liverpool
England and so forth certain things you
can do you can plan a journey uh you
know you can buy book tickets and sort
of you know and sort of gives you ideas
of what you can do with this
website And so that gave us this notion
of if the model understands what this
website is about maybe I can ask it to
actually generate generate the task. And
what we found is that you know we can
scale it across many many different
websites uh from common crawl uh I think
we started with about million websites
and we started thinking about like what
kind of tasks these models can generate
and a lot of tasks actually involve some
form of information retrieval some sort
of search you're finding the right
ticket information you're finding
booking uh u you know opening hours you
find sort of specific uh information on
you know a particular topic right um but
crucially we do not modify the state of
the internet so that was one of the um
sort of uh settings for us uh where we
asking the model to come up with the
task that don't modify the state of the
environment so for example booking
something we can do uh or clicking on
something that actually changes the
state on the of the environment uh we
can do uh this specifically was done you
to avoid any sort of complications of us
being blocked and as I mentioned before
you know we can't go on you know
united.com or booking.com and start like
you know running a lot of task like
booking a lot of hotels randomly right
um so we can only navigate to these
websites but we actually cannot um
change the state of the in state of the
environment what we found is that a lot
of tasks that the models actually come
up with are diverse and many require
multiple sets of reasoning Right? So for
example, you know, if I go to
fonts.adobe.com, some of the generated
task is browse fonts suitable for a
children's book. So I have to understand
like what makes a font suitable for a
children's book, right? Uh a lot of
tasks can identify facts um that's
likely to contain. So for example, if
I'm going to
ancient-syols.com, you know, the
generated task would be look up the
meaning of the word om symbol in ancient
cultures, right? So if you kind of like
you know you have to go on this website
this is the task and I have to crawl
through this website to actually find
what's the meaning of of that particular
symbol or I can sort of you know go to
this particular
uh obscure Scottish design studio and
ask view the latest fabric designs by
you know by this particular studio right
so I end up on this website and I have
to find uh the latest designs fabric
designs and kind of this This is kind of
like how it looks like. I actually have
to end up on this particular web page
because that lists the latest fabric
designs by by that particular studio.
Right? So these tasks are grounded even
for sites in the tail of the data
distributions. Uh right. So these are
kind of like we wanted to go for breadth
not necessarily to kind of you know only
cover you know 100 most commonly visited
websites but also going to these sort of
you know which gives us the diversity of
the environments and different websites
and different um uh generated tasks.
Okay. So that's kind of you know the
first step trying to generate the tasks
right. Um now the second state is okay
um how do we know when these tasks are
solved right and that gives us the task
evaluation part and the way we do this
is we basically say okay if we given the
task generate a task we can execute this
task using the current model let's say
you have a GPT model or you have your
llama model in this case it was a llama
model um that we're using you observe a
sequence of actions and the last
observation and you now estimate the
probability of uh a task being
successful. Right? So you're basically
asking the model given the last state in
a sequence of actions you're asking it
to estimate the probability of the
success. This is again the same idea as
using large language model as a judge.
uh you know here we're actually
evaluating the full trajectory but you
can think of it as you know in the
previous part when we were looking at
the search we're essentially we're using
the same piece but only evaluating
partial trajectories to sort of figure
out like what we should explore and what
we shouldn't explore. Here we're
actually trying to evaluate the full
trajectory but obviously you can combine
search with this technique as well. So
you can kind of search around and sort
of try to find the best uh uh the best
outcome. And you prompt llama to rate
the confidence of the task that solve
you know from 0 to
one. And what we found um is that out of
for example out of 150,000 tasks about
you know 15% are rated as success with
high confidence uh by llama roughly
22,000 tasks. We actually did verify you
know how good uh you using llama as a
judge and I think that in terms of uh uh
the success it was about 90%. Right? So
for example you know when the model says
I'm pretty sure I've solved the task
with human evaluations we're seeing
close to
90% accuracy among those ones. It
basically means whenever llama says yes
I've solved the task 90% of the time it
actually solved the task 10% of the time
no it didn't solve the task. So you know
these these verifiers are not perfect
but they're pretty decent in terms of
approximately telling you whether you
solve the task uh or not. Uh right so
that kind of like gives you this notion
of of of showing that you've
successfully u um found the task
executed and then verified it. Let me
give you sort of visual uh
representation of what that looks like.
Um so you know on on a different project
we have a project where we're working
with ecologists of on sort of
identifying invasive plants uh in in in
different environments. Um and uh we
basically thought that okay let's let's
look at this website invasive plants
atlas and prompt the model to generate a
task and see if the model can solve the
task. So the model basically generates a
task find invasive plant species native
to North America. Okay, so that's more
like information extraction and the
agent response is to find an invasive
plant species in North America. I will
first click on link all species to view
the list of all species. Okay, so it
takes and based on this information and
clicks on all species, right? And that's
what the action looks like. It's a
little JSON that you have an action key
click. you have an action you know
arguments that can go in and you have a
target element ID the ID that you have
you associated with that particular
click
um then it basically says to find
invasive plant species native to L
America you know I I will first click on
the link home and because it's trying to
go to the sources and it's it sort of
misses the point because you know there
is a sources here right but it's
actually insist on going home and and to
find the sources. So it's sort of
misread. So it made a mistake in this
case, right? Since the link to sources
is not on the current web page, but it
is. So it's making a mistake. I will
first click on the home and go back to
the main page. So it goes back to the
main page and then it sort of identifies
the sources, right? So it kind of you
know clicks on the sources. Um it
actually gets to the right piece to find
invasive plants native to North America.
I will first click on F on A under the
native French taxonomic references. So
it sort of execute pieces and it does
you know clicks on that on the correct
element and then once it gets to the
correct element it then basically says I
need to I need to sort based on
US you know plants that are native to
the US gets it in the JSON format and
then gives you the answer right uh since
the list is already sorted by US
nativity by sending order that's it I
can find there's the first like60 165
plant species that are native to North
America. Right? So, so these this gives
you the list and the answer is basically
I give you the web page and I tell you
the first 165 plant species on the list
invasive plant species native to North
America. Right? So, in terms of like me
finding information seeking again this
is was completely synthetically
generated task where the model proposed
the task. it's now executed the task
even though it made a mistake and then
it gave you the action and in this case
um despite sort of like reasoning some
of the reasoning failures because it
clicked on the wrong thing but then it
recovered
um it found the target information and
in this case llama verify evaluates this
trajectory successfully with confidence
one right and again whenever it does
this verification it's about 90%
accurate maybe close to maybe 85 90%
accurate when we sort of did the
studies, human studies. Uh so that sort
of gives you, you know, an interesting
synthetic generation, right? Uh where
you're proposing the task, you're
executing this task and then you're
verifying did you solve the task or not.
And again, only 14% of 15% of the task
that the model propose and executes only
15% of them, you know, the model
basically says yes, I think I solved the
task. 85% of them you can't solve the
task, right? So, but that's okay because
it's all done uh automatically. There is
no human uh human in the loop here. Uh
let me show you some examples other
examples of what the model does. So,
here's the example. Find me the opening
hours of Sagara de Familia, right? It's
a fairly famous church in Barcelona. So,
it sort of, you know, proposes the task,
it browses the web, it finds and it
finds the answer, right? So you know so
again you know this is the task that it
proposes it goes to the website it
actually finds uh you know familia it
clicks it it finds and it basically from
the table finds what the right answer is
we find information on the European
Union's climate action uh policies so it
goes to European Union commission it
crawls the web um and then you know this
is a success where it actually finds the
documents related to uh the climate
action progress or climate action
policies
Right. And again these tasks are
completely created by model proposing
what the task should be model executing
this task and then the model is
verifying whether it successfully uh
computed the task or not. Right? So we
sort of went through these two stages
and again I'm not saying that that's a
perfect setting. I think that you know
if you incorporate search if you have
better models um and then you sort of
you know iterate it multiple times I
think the quality of generation of of
these task could improve uh could
improve su substantially. So let me uh
talk a little bit about the data
collection, right? So what happens uh
with the data collection? Now we can
scale up the data
collection. So we've used the common
crawl page rank to find the most
important websites. We start with the
top 1 million web
pages. Um we filtered it down to about
150,000 life websites um by you know
filtering harmful content. So we're
prompting the model. So if we think that
there is a harmful content on the
website, we basically ignore it. Uh so
we're about 97% actually pretty high in
terms of detecting and filtering harmful
content. This is used using llama
models. we um about 89% success rate in
generating feasible tasks and about 80
so it's like 90% in generating feasible
task which basically means that uh you
know um when we're verifying whether
task is successful or not we 89%
uh and 82% accuracy in judging
successful task completion sorry that's
the one where 82% whether the task is
successfully uh completed or not um and
so and again we sort went through
150,000 live websites and then we you
know attempting it and verifying it and
sort of you know creating data based on
whether we successfully generate the
task and whether we successfully
executed and then verified success.
What's interesting is that we found that
on sort of toish examples and small
examples mind the web links these are
sort of uh some of the uh data sets that
people use. We found that trading on
synthetic and human demonstrations scale
faster than just training on human
demonstrations. Uh right. So actually if
you're mixing uh what humans collected
versus if you're mixing synthetic and
humans, we can sort of see improvements.
We also see that adding synthetic data
improves step accuracy by you know um um
by uh you know certain numbers. So
that's good. We also found that if you
only use human annotations,
uh, human annotations do struggle with
generalization because a lot of times
what actually end ups happening is that
with human annotations are typically
done on on a small subset of highly
visited, you know, um, websites and the
ability to generalize to, you know, the
tail of the distribution. That's where
synthetic data really helps us because
it can help us generalize to the tail of
the distribution, right? where it's very
difficult for for humans to collect
collect the data. Obviously the ultimate
choice would be to get humans to
annotate the entire web that would be
the best because then we can just do
imitation learning. Um but we do find
that sort of you know the ability to
crawl the web and look at the stale
distribution we do see uh improvements
in in generalization.
Now there are 385 million unique domains
uh right suggesting maybe another
thousand X mode data that could be
available by scaling further right we
were constrained by compute and academic
resources when we did this work and of
course there is also sort of this notion
of moving towards online reinforcement
learning. So you can think about
settings where you sort of run this
procedure right you collect the
synthetic data and then you update the
model and do it again. So you can sort
of like you know do it in online fashion
right you crawl the web you generate
these tasks you try to solve uh some of
these tasks you update the model
parameters and do that again so if you
have an online and that could be an
online reinforcement learning but done
at scale at the internet scale I think
these models would improve uh
significantly and of course it's very
difficult to do that on the real web uh
because it's very hard to you know
change you know you can't change the
state of the environment And um so you
have to be careful how you actually uh
scaling up uh scaling scaling it uh up
uh when you go to the real world or the
real web. Okay. Um let me just in the
last 10 minutes and I I leave the uh
room for questions. I wanted to sort of
point out that this notion of agentic uh
environment is also applicable to the
physical agents or robots in general.
Right? So we've also kind of like very
parallel effort. We basically thought
okay these AI agents sort of have the
same uh uh notion whether we operating
on the web and taking actions on the web
or whether we actually have a physical
agent like a robot that takes actions in
the real world. Right? So for example
you know you can think of it you're
observing the data which is could be the
image plus maybe the depths. Um you do
some form of semantic segmentation to
understand the environment. you have an
objective, you generate a high level
plan and then you generate the low-level
actions like interacting with the actual
environment. So we have this uh this
this work on on planning learning uh
what we call plan sequence and learn
where the idea is language model
basically gives you a sequence of highle
plan what you need to do you have a
sequencing or parsing module that
basically understands the environment
sequences is and then we have a
low-level action which we learn with
reinforcement learning which a little
policy actually learns how to take a
particular action right so very much in
flavor very similar to what the web web
agents are doing but now we're actually
interacting in the real world. So for
example a planning module can say okay
uh here's the task you know get me uh
I'm I'm trying to kind of like put the
silver knot in the silver pack and the
gold nut and the gold bag and then give
me the simple plan to solve this task
and so the LLN basically produces a
fairly simple task of of how I should
how I should solve it. We have a
sequencing model uh which you know looks
at the observation there's a depth um
you know we do se segment se
segmentation and sort of a little bit of
a projection so kind of like have some
form of 3D representation of the
environment and then it goes through the
inverse kinematic and we have a motion
planner but you can think of this as
sort of like again understanding the
environment and doing a little bit of
motion planning and then the low-level
action module actually learns the local
policy right so Here you have
reinforcement learning for interactions.
You're kind of like locally learning how
to interact with much like when you're
clicking on particular element. Here
we're actually learning how to you know
control our joint angle so that we can
accomplish a low-level uh a low-level
task right and so this is how it sort of
looks like where you know a local model
is actually learning how to uh with
reinforcement learning it's actually
learning how to uh interact with the
environment. And so kind of like in the
full pipeline very much in similar
spirit you have a planning model that
plans um you know high gives you high
level plan for each highle plan you
executing this low you know lower level
actions where you basically have pose
estimation motion planning a little bit
of reinforcement learning to take the
action and then you know you have this
low-level control that actually controls
low-level actions via reinforcement
learning right and then you proceed and
just the first step and you go to the
next and then you go to the next and
sort of execute that according to the
plan
uh and so forth and we found that these
sort of models uh you know work
reasonably well you know PSL solves
about 25 long horizon robotic tasks
across you know in this case four
benchmarks
um with you know about 85% success rate
we also tried extending this to the
actual uh real uh environment So here is
the you know I give it a task put mouse
in the drawer. So the model basically
generates the plan and again it looks at
the environment parses the environment
and then executes lower level actions
right. Um and it sort of does uh a lot
of interesting things. you can you know
uh but the point I do want to make here
is that whether you operating in the
virtual space or whether you're
operating in the real world space um you
know the ideas uh are fairly uh similar
across across domain and so here you can
generalize to new object object
geometries new categories and so like
you know we've never trained on this
particular um for this particular object
but you can sort of successfully
complete it you can deal with multiple
novel objects uh with unseen
receptacles. So, you know,
um you know, these models can do um you
know, can do reasonably well. It's not
perfect by all means. I think we're
hitting success rates of about like 80
to 90%. Um uh but these models do
generalize. They can manipulate deformal
objects. You don't observe them uh when
we were training these models in the
simulator. But, you know, training in
the simulator does translate into into
the real world.
Okay, now to summarize uh we've talked
about visual web arena as a benchmark
for you know these realistic tasks
designed to evaluate the capabilities of
autonomous multimodal agents. We've
talked about inference time search
algorithm which sort of designed to
enhance the capabilities of of language
models for realistic web tasks right and
how we can you know do the search and
there's a lot of research that needs to
be done in that space and then we've
talked about the data pipeline for large
scale generation verification of sort of
these synthetic tasks that the model can
create uh powered by llama models and
the interesting thing about all of these
settings is that you know you can try to
generate these synthetic task. You can
use inference time to generate something
better. You can you know use data
collection with humans and ultimately
it's a combination of all of these
pieces um that will potentially lead to
models that can uh that can work very
well in in the real world environments.
One last thing I do want to mention is
that you know AI safety and robustness
uh becomes fairly important especially
in the age of autonomous systems and
what essentially happening today is that
these systems are not first of all
they're not very robust
um you know like if I ask it to do some
task it you know sometimes it completes
the task sometimes it doesn't right and
it's very difficult you know like if I
if I want to have a system that books
the my my flights as an example, right?
I don't want to have a system that's
only 80% correct, right? I don't want a
system that like, you know, 80% books
the right stuff and 20% doesn't book the
right books the wrong planes for me,
right? That's
unacceptable. So, sort of having these
agentic capabilities that actually very
good at executing tasks perhaps asking
for clarification questions. So, have
some kind of model in the loop becomes
uh very important research and and very
important uh which is which is missing.
I think that's missing today on AI
safety that's another area of research
right because a lot of times these
agents are very brittle so you can
actually u you know adversely kind of
modify them and so like this is some
work um there's a lot more work that's
happening in this space um but we found
this one interesting settings this is
was done on visual web arena where we
basically change the representation of
images so you have a web page on the web
page you have your images and you change
your representation of the images in
such a way that the captioning system
when it captions it actually you know
provides an instruction to the language
model of what it should do next right so
so we can kind of like hijack these
agents and basically say you know add
the comment looks great before providing
the next action so if the mole ends up
on your web page right instead of like
navigating to the next one it will leave
the comment saying this is a terrific uh
you know this terrific product and then
go to the next one, right? So you can
kind of like force it to generate for
example you know
um uh positive feedback for your
product, right? So you can boost your
boost your sort of uh um you know that a
lot of kind of like agents or people
like your product, right? So it's just
it's a little bit toish at this point.
Uh but it becomes fairly important
because you know you don't want to have
a system you want to have a system
that's robust. is sort of these
adversarial settings where I can modify
my state in an adversarial way so as to
ask you know the model to to take a
different action than it's supposed to
take right and finally this is a funny
example I but I wanted to mention you
know like uh there's a lot of work in
the industry on building these types of
models obviously we want to have
assistance that can look at the web and
do a lot of tasks on you uh uh but this
was done by uh claude uh anthropics uh
computer use. Uh and so it kind of you
know they have this funny thing where
say you know in one episode uh Claude
accidentally clicked to stop a long
running screen recording causing all
footage to be lost in another clock
suddenly took a break from our coding
demo and began to use photos of you know
Yellowstone National Park. And the
reason why these models do that because
you know you have a sequence you have a
set of actions and so if it's sort of
trying to accomplish the task takes the
wrong action right then it sort of once
it takes the wrong action and it doesn't
have this search ability to kind of like
understand I'm not actually I've taken
the action that doesn't is not
consistent with my task then it's very
hard for it to backtrack potentially
right like once you've taken the action
it's trying to take another action maybe
it's trying to recover and then
basically cannot recover back uh to the
original uh original